CECELIA FOWLER

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

69

203-598-6307



dev@ceceliafowler.com



ceceliafowler.com



www.linkedin.com/in/ceceliafowler



https://github.com/cecelia001

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js

Express

MySQL

Postman

TDD/JEST

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with graduate level training in education and 4+ years managerial experience. Practical experience building applications from start to finish, including working with databases and APIs, performing unit testing, and implementing front-end frameworks. Lifelong learner with a diverse range of certifications and a strong desire to expand my skills.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

Master of Science | Education

Bachelor of Science | Education

2015

University of Bridgeport | Bridgeport, CT

Western CT State University | Danbury, CT

2013

PROJECTS

Advanced Git

JavaScript

React/Vue

HTML/CSS

Bootstrap

Roadtrip Social Planner

December 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Node.js, Bootstrap, JSON Web Token, Bcrypt

Worked with an international team to create a full stack app with 3rd party API integration and authorization.

Productivity Tracker

November 2022

Built with: JSON Web Token, Bcrypt, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Chakra UI

Inherited legacy code to implement authentication and authorization, allowing for user registration and login.

Monthly Expense Analysis

October 2022

Built with: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, MySQL, REST APIs

Full stack app designed to monitor monthly expenses and establish personalized budgets for different categories.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain

Developed 3 full stack apps featuring JavaScript, Node.js, React, MySQL, APIs, and more to demonstrate full stack proficiency and successful completion of a three-month intensive full-time bootcamp.

Head of Youth Services

Feb 2018 - Sept 2022

Howard Whittemore & Terryville Library

Supervised and trained staff of 9 and 15 volunteers. Effectively managed budgets totaling \$15k. Fostered 6 new partnerships within the community. Boosted attendance of programs by 35%.

Financial Consultant

Jan 2016 - Feb 2018

AXA Advisors

Advised a total of \$6 AUM in retirement accounts. Drove 15+ qualified leads per week. Communicated regularly with over 130 clients, using Salesforce. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams.

Classroom Teacher

Aug 2013 - Jan 2016

Regional District 16

Implemented positive and productive learning environment for 25+ children. Analyzed student performance and reported progress at weekly team meetings. Increased reading and math scores by 30%.